<?xml version='1.0'?>

<project>
        <name>GridSLAM</name>

        <author>
		<name>Dirk Haehnel</name>
		<email>dirk.haehnel@gmail.com</email>
		<url>http://seattle.intel-research.net/people/dhaehnel/</url>
	</author>
        <author>
		<name>Dieter Fox</name>
		<email>fox@cs.washington.edu</email>
		<url>http://www.cs.washington.edu/homes/fox/</url>
	</author>
        <author>
		<name>Wolfram Burgard</name>
		<email>burgard@informatik.uni-freiburg.de</email>
		<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~burgard</url>
	</author>
        <author>
		<name>Sebastian Thrun</name>
		<email>thrun@stanford.edu</email>
		<url>http://robots.stanford.edu</url>
	</author>

	<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~haehnel/old/research/scan-matching-fastslam/index.html</url>

        <briefdescription>
	 GridSLAM is an easy to use and understand  Rao-Blackwellized particle filer to learn
	 grid maps from laser range data.
	</briefdescription>

        <description>
	The ability to learn a consistent model of its environment is
        a prerequisite for autonomous mobile robots. A particularly
        challenging problem in acquiring environment maps is that of
        closing loops; loops in the environment create challenging
        data association problems. This work presents a novel
        algorithm that combines Rao-Blackwellized particle filtering
        and scan matching. In our approach scan matching is used for
        minimizing odometric errors during mapping. A probabilistic
        model of the residual errors of scan matching process is then
        used for the resampling steps. This way the number of samples
        required is seriously reduced. Simultaneously we reduce the
        particle depletion problem that typically prevents the robot
        from closing large loops. We present extensive experiments
        that illustrate the superior performance of our approach
        compared to previous approaches.
        </description>

	<image> 
		<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~haehnel/old/images/wean4th-fastlam-anim-small.gif</url>
		<thumbnailurl>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~haehnel/old/images/wean4th-fastlam-anim-small.gif
</thumbnailurl>
		<description>Mapping Animation</description>
	</image>


        <requirement>
        Linux/Unix, GCC 3.3/4.x
        </requirement>
        <requirement>
	CARMEN
	</requirement>
        <requirement>
	Qt
	</requirement>

	<map>grid maps</map>

	<input>The approach takes raw laser range data and
	(scan-matched) odometry.</input>

	<logformat> 
	Carmen log format as well as Dirk Haehnel's rec format
	</logformat>

	<paper>
		<title> A highly efficient FastSLAM algorithm for generating cyclic maps of large-scale environments from raw laser range measurements</title>
		<authorlist>D. Haehnel, D. Fox, W. Burgard, S. Thrun</authorlist>
		<publishedin>In Proc. of the Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</publishedin>
		<year>2003</year>
		<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~haehnel/old/papers/haehnel.iros03.pdf</url>
	</paper>

</project>
