<?xml version='1.0'?>

<project>
        <name>DP-SLAM</name>

        <author>
		<name>Austin Eliazar</name>
		<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/~eliazar</url>
	</author>
        <author>
		<name>Ronald Parr</name>
		<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/%7Eparr</url>
	</author>

	<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/~parr/dpslam/</url>

        <briefdescription>
	 DP-SLAM aims to achieve truly simultaneous localization and
	 mapping without landmarks. While DP-SLAM is compatible with
	 techniques that correct maps when a loop is closed, we have
	 found that DP-SLAM is accurate enough that no special loop
	 closing techniques are required in most cases.  DP-SLAM makes
	 only a single pass over the sensor data.
         DP-SLAM works by maintaining a joint probability distribution
         over maps and robot poses using a particle filter. This
         allows DP-SLAM to maintain uncertainty about the map over
         multiple time steps until ambiguities can be resolved. This
         prevents errors in the map from accumulating over time.
	</briefdescription>

        <description>
        DP-SLAM uses a particle filter to maintain a joint probability
        distribution over maps and robot positions.  This would be
        expensive without some clever data structures since it would
        require a complete copy of the entire occupancy grid for every
        particle, and would require making copies of the maps during
        the resampling phase of the particle filter.  The figure below
        conceptually shows an ancestry of particles and map updates,
        with leaves of the ancestry tree pointing to maps.  (Think of
        each red dot in the ancestry tree as a sampled robot position
        and the black lines around the red dot as the new observations
        associated with the current robot position.  The gray lines
        show piece of the map inherited from the previous particle.)
        Notice that all maps in this example will agree with the
        initial observation.  The two leftmost maps will agree on the
        observations made by the left child of the root, while the two
        rightmost maps will agree with the observations made by the
        right child of the root.  It would be a waste of memory and
        time to store and repeatedly copy these map sections every
        time a particle is resampled.  Instead, we use a single
        occupancy grid which stores an observation tree at each
        square.  As shown below, each particle inserts its
        observations into the global grid.  These are stored as a
        balanced tree, indexed on a unique ID assigned to each
        particle.  The computer science part of the DP-SLAM project
        involves the algorithms and analysis to show that these data
        structures can be maintained efficiently.
	</description>

	<image> 
		<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/~parr/dpslam/Wean.html</url>
		<thumbnailurl>http://www.cs.duke.edu/~parr/dpslam/wean-thumb.png</thumbnailurl>
		<description>Wean Hall</description>
	</image>
	<image> 
		<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/~parr/dpslam/C-Wing.html</url>
		<thumbnailurl>http://www.cs.duke.edu/~parr/dpslam/3cm25-icon.gif</thumbnailurl>
		<description>C-Wing</description>
	</image>



        <requirement>
	Linux
	</requirement>

	<map>grid maps</map>

	<input>The approach takes raw laser range data and odometry.</input>


	<paper>
		<title>DP-SLAM: Fast, Robust Simultainous Localization
                  and Mapping Without Predetermined Landmarks</title>
		<authorlist>Austin Eliazar, Ronald Parr</authorlist>
		<publishedin>IJCAI</publishedin>
		<year>2003</year>
		<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/%7Eparr/ijcai03.ps.gz</url>
	</paper>
	<paper>
		<title>DP-SLAM 2.0</title>
		<authorlist>Austin Eliazar, Ronald Parr</authorlist>
		<url>http://www.cs.duke.edu/%7Eparr/dpslam2.pdf</url>
	</paper>

	<license>
        This Program is provided by Duke University and the authors as
        a service to the research community. It is provided without
        cost or restrictions, except for the User's acknowledgment
        that the Program is provided on an "As Is" basis and User
        understands that Duke University and the authors make no
        express or implied warranty of any kind.  Duke University and
        the authors specifically disclaim any implied warranty or
        merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose, and make
        no representations or warranties that the Program will not
        infringe the intellectual property rights of others. The User
        agrees to indemnify and hold harmless Duke University and the
        authors from and against any and all liability arising out of
        User's use of the Program.
	</license>

</project>
